# Vaibhav Kumar Salesforce Developer

■ vaibhavks23@gmail.com

9953473737

in linkedin.com/in/vaibhavkumar23

#### Profile

To be a successful professional and to secure employment with a reputable company. Having the experience of 3 year as a Software Engineer and include relevant experience of 1 year as a Salesforce Developer, managing team and having a problem solving capacity.

#### **Professional Experience**

Cloudsheer Consulting (October 2024 -Present)

#### Salesforce Developer

- Worked on the Migration of Data from one org to another.
- Worked on Test Class, Apex Class, Flows, Validation Rules

Act21 Softwares (Pvt) Ltd (December 2021 -July 2024)

#### **ICICI NPS using Salesforce**

- Spearheaded the creation and implementation of functionalities for the ICICI National Pension System (NPS) project.
- Initiated **Data migration from ICICI** application to Salesforce for seamless integration through Data Loader.
- Leveraged Apex Class, Apex triggers and Asynchronous Apex for automation.

#### User Management (HDFC)

• Integrated different api's related the User Management which include the process of onboarding the user and different functionality related to the user.

#### Calculations of incentives (HDFC & BAJAJ)

- Developed and maintained PL/SQL procedures to generate input JSON and calculate incentives based on bank policies.
- Conducted development, debugging, and testing activities.

Yatra Online Private Limited.( January 2021 to September 2021)

#### Online Boarding Pass using Spring MVC

- Contributed to a project aimed at providing online boarding passes directly to passengers via email for an airline company.
- Developed the project using Spring MVC in Java EE.

# ACPL Systems Pvt Ltd. (Internship)

Intern and trainee

• Collaborated with the testing team, gaining hands-on experience in Testing Automation using Selenium.

#### Education

2017 - 2021	BTech (Computer Science Engineering) University Institute of Engineering Technology, MDU
2016	12th , Delhi Public School , Maruti Kunj
2014	10th.Delhi Public School, Maruti Kuni

### **Technical Skills**

Salesforce Skills: Admin, Salesforce Development, Apex Class, Apex Triggers, Batch Apex, Validation Rule, Flows, LWC.

JAVA Skills: JAVA, Spring Boot, MVC

Database Skills: MYSQL, SQL, SQL, SOSL

Basics of HTML, Javascript, CSS.

#### **Soft Skills**

• Communication Skills

• Team Management

• Problem Solving

• Analytic Skills

• Presentation Skills.

# Certifications

• Platform Developer I Certificate from Salesforce.

• JAVA (Basic) from Hackerrank.

• SQL Fundamental from SoloLearn

• Fundamental Course In Salesforce Certified Associate

• HTML Fundamental from SoloLearn

• Javascript Fundamental from SoloLearn

#### **Personal Details**

Father Name: Prem Prasad Singh

Birth Date: 23 June 1998

**Current Location : Gurgaon**